<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Anthony Castañeda</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Anthony Castañeda</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:45:36 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Married</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/married/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/married/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-passing&#34;&gt;Time passing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How long have I been &lt;a href=&#34;https://anthonycastaneda.github.io/married/&#34;&gt;married&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Car Trucks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-they-load-them-cars-on-them-trucks&#34;&gt;How do they load them cars on them trucks?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loading cars onto car-carrying trucks (also known as &lt;strong&gt;auto transporters&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;car haulers&lt;/strong&gt;) is a well-coordinated process that involves a combination of ramps, hydraulic systems, and skilled drivers. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of how the loading process generally works:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-preparation&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Preparation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vehicle Inspection&lt;/strong&gt;: Before loading, each car is typically inspected for damage. This is important for liability reasons and to document the car’s condition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arranging the Cars&lt;/strong&gt;: The cars are often arranged in the order they need to be loaded, ensuring that the heaviest vehicles are loaded first or in such a way as to balance the weight across the trailer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-use-of-hydraulic-lifts-or-ramps&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Use of Hydraulic Lifts or Ramps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hydraulic Lifts&lt;/strong&gt;: Some car carriers have hydraulic ramps that can be raised and lowered. The ramps lower to the ground, allowing the cars to be driven or rolled onto the transporter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manual Ramps&lt;/strong&gt;: On some car carriers, manual ramps are used. These ramps are usually set up at an angle to allow the car to drive up with ease. Some carriers have multiple levels with ramps to accommodate more vehicles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tilt Beds&lt;/strong&gt;: In some cases, the car hauler has a tilt-bed design. The entire lower deck of the truck tilts to a low angle, making it easier to drive the cars directly onto the carrier. This is common for single-vehicle carriers or smaller transporters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-loading-process&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Loading Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Driving onto the Trailer&lt;/strong&gt;: Once the ramps are positioned, cars are driven onto the trailer, usually in a careful, controlled manner. The driver of the car usually follows instructions, sometimes with a guide to help them park the vehicle in the right spot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leveling the Trailer&lt;/strong&gt;: The trucks may have adjustable air suspension or hydraulics to level the trailer once a car has been loaded, ensuring that the load is balanced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securing the Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt;: After loading, the vehicles are secured using specialized tie-downs, straps, or wheel chocks. Some car carriers use &lt;strong&gt;wheel straps&lt;/strong&gt; that hold the wheels in place, while others may use &lt;strong&gt;frame straps&lt;/strong&gt; to secure the car by the chassis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Winches&lt;/strong&gt;: In some cases, a winch may be used to pull a car onto the trailer if it cannot be driven (e.g., if the car is inoperable). The winch is a mechanical system with a strong cable that can pull the car up the ramps.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-multi-level-carriers&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Multi-Level Carriers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many car carriers have two or three levels (decks) to maximize capacity. The lower deck can often accommodate larger vehicles like SUVs, while smaller vehicles go on the upper decks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loading the Upper Decks&lt;/strong&gt;: For the upper levels, cars may need to be driven up ramps or lifted via a hydraulic system that moves the vehicles into place on the higher levels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-securing-the-load&#34;&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Securing the Load&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After all the cars are loaded onto the transporter, each vehicle is carefully secured with straps and/or chains. The driver will check the stability of the load to ensure that the cars will not move during transit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Height and Clearance Check&lt;/strong&gt;: Drivers also ensure that the height of the load doesn’t exceed legal limits for road transport.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-unloading&#34;&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Unloading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When unloading, the process is essentially the reverse. The ramps or lifts are lowered, and the cars are driven off the transporter one by one, or in some cases, they may be winched off if they&amp;rsquo;re not in working condition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-of-methods&#34;&gt;Summary of Methods&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ramp Loading&lt;/strong&gt;: Cars are driven up a ramp onto the carrier.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hydraulic Lifts&lt;/strong&gt;: The trailer uses hydraulic mechanisms to tilt or elevate the vehicle onto the transporter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winches&lt;/strong&gt;: Used to pull inoperable vehicles onto the carrier.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securing&lt;/strong&gt;: Vehicles are strapped or chained to prevent movement during transit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The entire process requires careful planning to ensure the vehicles are loaded safely and securely, and it often involves several people working together to coordinate each step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entra ID</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/entra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/entra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;entra-powershell&#34;&gt;Entra PowerShell&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To work with Enterprise Applications in Azure using PowerShell, particularly for Entra ID (previously Azure AD), you&amp;rsquo;ll typically use the &lt;strong&gt;AzureAD&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft.Graph&lt;/strong&gt; module for interacting with these resources. Below is an example of a PowerShell script that demonstrates how to interact with an &lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Application&lt;/strong&gt; in Entra ID using the &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft.Graph&lt;/strong&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft.Graph PowerShell Module&lt;/strong&gt;: If you don&amp;rsquo;t have it installed, use the following to install it:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Chicken Curry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making an &lt;strong&gt;authentic chicken curry&lt;/strong&gt; involves a blend of spices, slow cooking, and a bit of patience. Depending on the region, chicken curry recipes vary, but I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through a basic, flavorful recipe that can be adapted to suit many Indian and South Asian styles. This recipe focuses on traditional ingredients and techniques for an aromatic, rich, and delicious chicken curry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;authentic-chicken-curry-recipe&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentic Chicken Curry Recipe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Chicken Marinade:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snare Drum Tuning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/snare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>anthony@anthonycastaneda.com (Anthony Castañeda)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/snare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tuning a snare drum properly is crucial for achieving a clear, crisp sound with good responsiveness. The snare drum is often considered one of the most important pieces of the drum kit, so tuning it correctly is essential for overall sound quality. Here’s a step-by-step guide to help you tune your snare drum:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-youll-need&#34;&gt;Tools You’ll Need&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drum Key&lt;/strong&gt; (most important tool)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuner (Optional)&lt;/strong&gt; – Some drummers use a drum tuner for precision, but it&amp;rsquo;s not strictly necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Muffling Pads or Dampening Rings (Optional)&lt;/strong&gt; – For specific tone adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-tune-the-batter-head-top-head&#34;&gt;Step 1: &lt;strong&gt;Tune the Batter Head (Top Head)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loosen the Tension Rods&lt;/strong&gt;: Begin by loosening all the tension rods on the batter head (the top head you strike) by turning them counterclockwise with your drum key. Do this evenly, so the head is loose and there is no tension.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
